# Len Lester

Glendale, CA 91206 818-530-3486 lenster921@gmail.com Website LinkedIn

Highly qualified Full Stack Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in web development and software applications. Proactive team player with keen insight at developing, managing, and scaling various initiatives across various multi-disciplinary environments. Proficient working within UI frameworks while ensuring technical usability and accessibility for positive user experiences. Willing to work remotely and relocate to New York or EU.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript • PHP • Node.JS • TypeScript • SQL • NoSql • MongoDB • DynamoDB • React • Next.JS • HTML • CSS • Redux • Tailwind • Webpack • Web Components • Express • Web Sockets • Git • Jenkins • Docker • AWS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance - Glendale, CA

01/2023 - Present

#### **Freelance Software Engineer**

Develop and manage various web projects utilizing Next.js, Typescript, and other contemporary web technologies. Compose tools and features with emphasis on intuitive user experience.

Key Competencies: TypeScript, Next.Js, Node.Js, HTML, CSS, Application Development

# Acquired 2,500+ unique visitors within 3 months by creating mobile application for Doopmarketer

- Surveyed market, determining strengths and needs of product
- Utilized component libraries like Chakra UI to display collect relevant information
- Extracted data from various sources using Ethers.JS in a Node.js serverless API

# Age Of Learning, Inc. / ABCmouse.com - Glendale, CA Senior Software Engineer

10/2010 - 12/2022

03/2018 - 12/2022

Worked on all end-to-end development process updates, utilizing JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Docker, and AWS services.Led implementation for adaptive learning engine, while ensuring compliance with company goals. Worked across teams on software and production implementation.

Key Competencies: JavaScript, PHP, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, AWS, Docker, Jenkins, Process Improvement

#### Accelerated productivity by 300% for Curriculum Specialist team

- Assessed strengths and weaknesses of potential databases such as Neptune Graph
- Generated backend API for migration of relational tables to graph database
- Partnered with curriculum specialists, creating tools for mapping taxonomies on ABCMouse

#### Saved \$100K per month by improving management of testing environments

- Created APIs to eliminate running EC2 instances and go live for limited times
- Built a frontend tool to allow product teams to remove or extend the life of their EC2 instances
- Tested products to ensure compliance and efficiency

#### Reduced development time 40% by producing faster, more efficient proprietary JavaScript framework

- Evaluated modern frameworks, to consider most important functionality and utilities
- Implemented proprietary JavaScript framework while ensuring compliance with needs of company
- Produced base component libraries for managing, organizing, and storing data

#### Expedited development time by 40%, enhancing end-to-end developer experience

- Investigated tactics and strategies as employed by in-house marketing team
- Guided developers on integrating new UI framework with company vision
- Crafted multiple marketing pages using new framework

# Decreased by 60% development time of content tools and money spent for dedicated engineers

- Programmed generic JavaScript/JSON form builder
- Surveyed project managers and product owners, gaining insight on additional form elements needed
- Built specific form elements to align with differing product needs

Software Engineer III 06/2015 - 03/2018

Developed various curriculum management tools, delivering helpful features and improvements with solid technical foundations. Composed framework for creating tools to facilitate the creation and deployment of content for products.

Key Competencies: JavaScript, PHP, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, AngularJS, User Experience, Process Improvement

# Developed series of JavaScript tools to prepare new product launch

- Negotiated with product owners and project managers on gathering requirements for tools
- Designed suite of tools in preparation for launch of new product
- Verified that tools complied with product needs in collaboration with game designers and other stakeholders

Software Engineer II 04/2013 - 06/2015

Collaborated across teams to the ABCMouse's site from Flash/ActionScript to HTML/JavaScript, ensuring better end-to-end user experience. Designed tools that enabled animators to create 200+ high-quality animations for activities and games on revamped site.

Key Competencies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ActionScrip/Flash, PHP, MYSQL, Research & Development, Mentoring

# Optimized time and revenue by streamlining animation development process

- Developed tool to deconstruct Flash Animations into a images and metadata
- Created and optimized JavaScript Animation Player to allow for 1:1 animation
- Trained team of programmers on how to execute tools, along with troubleshooting needs

Flash Developer 10/2010 - 04/2013

Designed and implemented key features, increasing user engagement. Developed app's first iteration of Admin System, using JavaScript front-end PHP and MySQL back-end, resulting in faster release times and better user experience.

Key Competencies: Flash/ActionScript, PHP, MYSQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Web Development, Data Structures

Delivered content 200% faster with first iteration of Admin system

#### **EDUCATION**

California State University: Chico - Chico, CA Bachelor Of Arts - Linguistics